jordan wirfs-brock

498 Parkview Ave Golden, CO 80401 jordanwb@gmail.com 303-884-7591

website: **jordanwb.com** twitter: @jordanwb linkedin: bit.ly/JWBlinkedin

nutshell

Jordan is a first-year PhD student in Information Science. Her research focuses on how unexpected mechanisms—sound, taste, participatory experiences—can help people understand quantitative data. She has over ten years of professional experiences as a journalist, data analyst, producer, program manager and designer focused making complex information approachable.

education

University of Colorado Boulder, CO

PhD student in Information Science Began August 2017

University of Colorado Boulder, CO MA in Newsgathering May 2011

Graduate Certificate in Environment, Policy and Society

Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge, MA

SB in Aeronautic and Astronautic Engineering May 2006

Minor in Literature

work experience

Inside Energy / Rocky Mountain PBS

Denver, CO 2014 - 2017 Data Journalist

Produced stories for web, radio and TV about the energy industry; experimented with creative techniques like stop-motion animation and data sonification; collaborated with a team of reporters on investigative projects; performed at live events; practiced audience-driven storytelling; established data-driven culture for a start-up media organization

The Piton Foundation Denver, CO Data Curator; Product Manager 2011 - 2013

Analyzed socioeconomic data and community indicators; co-founded Floodlight, a tool for digital storytelling; grant-writing, product/technology development, outreach and community training

Rocky Mountain Investigative News Network

Denver, CO 2010 - 2011 *Investigative Reporting Intern*

Researched and wrote in-depth stories; produced multi-media packages including web graphics and interactive maps; data and public records analysis

Environmental Protection Agency, National Center for Environmental Research Washington, DC Science Journalism Intern Summer 2009

Summarized EPA-funded research for public audiences; created presentations and internal publications showcasing air quality/atmospheric chemistry research

Center for Environmental Journalism, University of Colorado Boulder, CO Graduate Research Assistant 2008 - 2010

Assistant to Ted Scripps Fellowship; coordinated weekly seminar speakers; maintained program website

Kwangju Foreign School

High School Teacher; Princeton In Asia fellow

Gwangju, Korea 2006 - 2007

Taught Biology, Physics, Pre-Calculus, Model U.N., Modern World History, Health/PE; coached cross-country, basketball; advisor for yearbook + art-lit magazine

training + teaching	Society of Professional Journalists/Google Newslab Trainer Teach hands-on workshops in technology, mapping, data visualization, immersive media and more at newsrooms and classrooms	2017 - 2018
	Designing and Leading Hands-On Workshops	
	SRCCON - "Let's create a roadmap for user testing and feedback in newsrooms"	2017
	SRCCON - "Can we pair program the news?"	2016
	SRCCON - "Data audioization workshop"	2015
	Society of Professional Journalists Denver Workshop - Introductory Data Skills	2016
speaking	TEDxMileHighWomen - "Your Relationship With Energy Is Broken. Let's Fix It."	2016
speaking	Computer Assisted Reporting Conference - "30 Energy Data Story Ideas in 60 Minutes"	2016
	The Aspen Challenge, Denver	2014
	Colorado Library Consortium Spring Workshops Keynote	2014
	Obama for America Colorado Citizen Engagement Roundtable, Ignite Session	2013
	Knight Media Learning Seminar	2013
	National Neighborhood Indicators Partnership Meeting	2011, 2012
	Denver Regional Council of Governments Regional Data Summit	2012, 2013
	Western Arts Federation Symposium	2012
awards	2017 University of Colorado Data Visualization Contest, 1st place - "Indian Lands and Fossil Fuel Resources" 2017 Public Radio News Directors Incorporated Award, 1st place independent podcast - <i>Out There</i> , "High on Failure" 2017 Heartland Regional Emmy Nominee, informational short - "What Does The Clean Power Plan Mean For You?"	
	2016 Illinois Humanities People-Powered Publishing Fellow - Project: Reciprocal Podcasting 2016 National Headliner Award, 2nd place radio series - "Blackout"	
	2016 Regional Murrow, investigative radio - "Abandoned Wells" (data journalist supporting reporter Stephanie Joyce)	
	2015 National Headliner Award, 2nd place radio feature - "How You're Invested In Oil An journalist supporting reporter Dan Boyce)	ıd Gas" (data
skills	Data and Relational Databases / Excel, SQL, Python (with pandas and Jupyter) Mapping + GIS / ArcGIS software, Google Fusion Tables, TileMill, Carto	
	Web Design + Programming / JavaScript, HTML, CSS, GitHub	
	Data Design / Illustrator, Tableau, d3.js	
	Storytelling / Audio editing, podcast production, animation, video storytelling	
	, J	

Trail and Ultra-Running / Six-time 100-mile run finisher; 48-hour, 72-hour and 10-day races;

member of Girls Heart Rockets, a space and science-themed all-women relay team

interests

Writing / essays, poetry, fiction Home brewer + craft beer enthusiast

Drawing / sketch-notes, comics, illustrations

MIT Varsity Athletics / basketball, cross-country, outdoor track